####################################################################################################################################
# EXPLANATION of files in PolyTrendMatrices.zip      
# Yufei Wei, Lund University
# weiyufei2014@outlook.com


# The pixels in the result are viewed as unqualified if they fulfill at least one following criterion. 
##### For a single pixel in the result, at least one NDVI values in the whole time span is smaller than 0.
##### For a single pixel in the result, during the whole time span, the number of NDVI pixels that have a difference of less than 0.000001 comparing to the ones that represent adjacent years is larger than or equal to 3 times the number of NDVI pixels of the whole time span divided by 4.
##### For all matrices except SlopeMatrix.txt, the value of unqualified pixles is -12000!!


# The pixels in the result are viewed as excluded if they are qualified pixels but are out of the desired range selected by the user.
##### For all matrices except SlopeMatrix.txt, the value of excluded pixles is -11000!!

All .txt files can be opened in WordPad, Matlab, Excel, ArcGIS, etc. and may appear unrecognized code when opened in Notepad.
####################################################################################################################################

# meanNDVIMatrix.txt -- Mean NDVI value of each pixel during the time period.
# minNDVIMatrix.txt -- Minimum NDVI value of each pixel during the time period.
# maxNDVIMatrix.txt -- Maximum NDVI value of each pixel during the time period.
# difNDVIMatrix.txt -- Differences in NDVI values of each pixel during the time period.
##### Normalized Difference Vegetation Index (NDVI) ranges from -1 to 1. It is used to qualify the density of plant growth. The formula is: NDVI = (NIR - VIS) / (NIR + VIS), where NIR stands for spectral reflectance measured in near-infrared spectral location and VIS means spectral reflectance measured in visible (red) spectral location.
##### Positive values of NDVI represent vegetation. The higher the value is, the higher density the vegetation has. Zero values of NDVI represent bare lands or rocks without vegetation. Negative values of NDVI represent water, clouds or snow. Negative values are viewed as unqualified data in this algorithm.


# TrendTypeMatrix.txt -- Trend type of each pixel.3~cubic, 2~quadratic, 1~linear, 0~No_trend, -1~concealed
## Cubic:
##### The pattern of vegetation trends can be fitted by a cubic polynomial.
##### The net change of vegetation amount can be detected when the statistical significance level in a t-test is α.
## Quadratic:
##### The pattern of vegetation trends can be fitted by a quadratic polynomial.
##### The net change of vegetation amount can be detected when the statistical significance level in a t-test is α.
## Linear:
##### The pattern of vegetation trends can be fitted by a linear polynomial.
##### The net change of vegetation amount can be detected when the statistical significance level in a t-test is α.
## No-trend:
##### The pattern of vegetation trends can neither be fitted by a cubic, quadratic, nor linear polynomial.
##### No net change of vegetation amount can be detected when the statistical significance level in a t-test is α.
## Concealed:
##### The pattern of vegetation trends can be fitted by a cubic polynomial or a quadratic polynomial.
##### No net change of vegetation amount can be detected when the statistical significance level in a t-test is α.


SlopeMatrix.txt -- Linear slope value that showing the net changes of NDVI during the whole time period of each pixel.
##### The extreme dark-blue pixels refer to unqualified and/or excluded pixles.
##### NaN in the matrix represents unqualified and/or excluded pixles.

DirectionMatrix.txt -- For each pixel, if the linear slope value is negative,the value of direction will be -1, otherwise is 1.
##### Positive: In general, the net change of NDVI increases. 
##### Insignificant: In general, the net change of NDVI decreases.


SignificanceMatrix.txt -- For each pixel, if the trend type belongs to "cubic", "quadratic" or "linear" the value will be 1, otherwise is -1.
##### Significant: The trend type is cubic, quadratic or linear. 
##### Insignificant: The trend type is no-trend or concealed. 


                   